Contact

8655689919 (Mobile) alimustafaats24@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ialimustufa (LinkedIn)

www.ted.com/talks/ ali_mustafa_shaikh_crowd_sourcing_ (Other) iali.dev (Personal) g.page (Other)

Top Skills

Web Technologies IoT
Java

Certifications

Google Studio

Launching into Machine Learning Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow (Grade Achieved: 100.0%) How Google does Machine Learning

Honors-Awards

State Level Paper Presentation Competetion Transform Maharashtra Microsoft Student Partners 2019/20 IEEE into Focus 2019 Grand Prize -Networking

National Level Project Competetion

Ali Mustufa Shaikh

Software Innovator @Intel | Google Certified Educator | #TEDx Speaker | Cloud & ML Trainer | Microsoft Student Partner Mumbai

Summary

I am a 23yr old with a vision to make students realize their potential and rise above the bar of college curriculum and experiment while they study so that they don't waste their professional years doing so!

The Idea is to make more Leaders and not merely followers! and to keep that alive I regularly interact with a lot of students who have the potential, who are doing exceptional things and I feel these big companies can enable them to do more!

Designed a course named Machine Learning Fast Track curated for students delivered in-person by me & my team. I have trained more than 5K students hands-on and 50K+ students through seminars & Workshops. This is the Part of regular engagement with those who matter for the future.

I have demonstrated a history of community management, especially for developers and students! leading the Community of Google Crowdsource in India & neighboring countries by influencing them for contributing & designing+running campaigns in almost 100+ Chapters. I served GDG Mumbai for 2 years from being a Volunteer to co-organizer. Currently, I am the co-organizer of Google Cloud Developer Community, Mumbai, and the Lead Ambassador of IEEE Collabratec in India!

Inspired by my journey I was approached for giving my 1st TEDx Talk in Mumbai. I was also featured by a national newspaper in Kerala, by TOI in Gujrat and have been the youngest speaker in most of the AI/ML conferences hosted by IEEE and Google in India!

Can I help you? If yes, let's connect & Talk!

Experience

IEEE Computer Society SYP
Marketing Lead - Startegic Initiatives
July 2020 - Present (2 months)

IEEE

1 year 6 months

IEEE Collabratec Usability Advisory Member April 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months)

This group will contain selected users within IEEE Collabratec who will provide key feedback on proposed platform function and features changes relating to usability and the User Interface (UI).

Lead Ambassador IEEE Collabratec March 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

IamRemarkable #IamRemarkable facilitator December 2019 - Present (9 months)

#lamRemarkable is an initiative empowering women and underrepresented groups to speak openly about their accomplishments in the workplace and beyond, thereby breaking modesty norms and glass ceilings.

As a facilitator, my role involves hosting workshops and being an ambassador for #lamRemarkable within my personal and professional networks.

To learn more and join the initiative visit: g.co/lamRemarkable

Studysid Micro Enterprunner May 2017 - December 2017 (8 months) Mumbai Area, India

Startupp
Campus Ambassador
May 2017 - August 2017 (4 months)
Mumbai Area, India

MCaffeine Digital marketing May 2017 - June 2017 (2 months) Mumbai SoftechSolutions Lecturer April 2016 - July 2016 (4 months) Kalyan Area, India

Education

A. P. Shah Institute of Technology, Thane
Bachelor's degree, Information Technology · (2016 - 2020)

M. H. Saboo Siddik Polytechnic, Byculla Diploma, Information Technology · (2013 - 2016)